{
   "questions":[
    {
      "question":"Who co-founded Hotmail in 1996?",
      "options":{
          "A":"Shawn Fanning",
          "B":"Ada Byron Lovelace",
          "C":"Sabeer Bhatia",
          "D":"Ray Tomlinson"
        },
        "answer":"C"
    },
	  {
      "question":"Who is the husband of Goddess Lakshmi?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Lord Shiva",
        "B":"Lord Vishnu",
        "C":"Lord Bramha",
        "D":"Lord Indra"
      },
      "answer":"B"
    },
    {
      "question":"Who killed Narakasura?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Lord Naryana",
        "B":"Lord Shiva",
        "C":"Lord Krishna",
        "D":"Lord Rama"
      },
      "answer":"C"
    },
    {
      "question":"Which oil is traditionally used to lit lamps during Diwali?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Olive Oil",
        "B":"Vegetable Oil",
        "C":"Corn Oil",
        "D":"Mustard Oil"
      },
      "answer":"D"
    },
    {
      "question":"Who was the first president of USA?",
      "options":{
        "A":"George Washington",
        "B":"Donald Trump",
        "C":"Barack Obama",
        "D":"George W. Bush"
      },
      "answer":"A"
    },
    {
      "question":"The first Thanksgiving lasted for how many days?",
      "options":{
        "A":"1 Day",
        "B":"2 Days",
        "C":"3 Days",
        "D":"5 Days"
      },
      "answer":"C"
    },
    {
      "question":"How many US states start with letter N?",
      "options":{
        "A":"4",
        "B":"7",
        "C":"8",
        "D":"9"
      },
      "answer":"C"
    },
    {
      "question":"Which team won the IPL (2009)?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Deccan Chargers",
        "B":"Chennai Super Kings",
        "C":"Mumbai Indians",
        "D":"Delhi Daredevils"
      },
      "answer":"A"
    },
	  {
      "question":"Who is the current President of India?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Ram Nath Kovind",
        "B":"Pratibha Patil",
        "C":"Pranab Mukherjee",
        "D":"K R Narayanan"
      },
      "answer":"A"
    },
	  {
      "question":"'OS' computer abbreviation usually means ?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Order of Significance",
        "B":"Open Software",
        "C":"Operating System",
        "D":"Optical Sensor"
      },
      "answer":"C"
    },
    {
      "question":"Who is the father of Geometry?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Aristotle",
        "B":"Euclid",
        "C":"Pythagoras",
        "D":"Kepler"
      },
      "answer":"B"
    },
    {
      "question":"Michael Jackson is a distinguished person in the field of?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Pop Music",
        "B":"Jounalism",
        "C":"Sports",
        "D":"Acting"
      },
      "answer":"A"
    },
    {
      "question":"Which city is known as 'Electronic City of India'?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Mumbai",
        "B":"Hyderabad",
        "C":"Guragon",
        "D":"Bangalore"
      },
      "answer":"D"
    },
    {
      "question":"The World Environment Day is celebrated on",
      "options":{
        "A":"April 7",
        "B":"June 5",
        "C":"August 6",
        "D":"June 16"
      },
      "answer":"B"
    },
    {
      "question":"In which decade was the Internet first implemented?",
      "options":{
        "A":"1940s",
        "B":"1950s",
        "C":"1960s",
        "D":"1980s"
      },
      "answer":"C"
    },
    {
      "question":"When was John Deere founded?",
      "options":{
        "A":"1837",
        "B":"1833",
        "C":"1839",
        "D":"1836"
      },
      "answer":"A"
    },
    {
      "question":"Which International star performed in the opening ceremony of 2013 IPL?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Jennifer Lopez",
        "B":"Akon",
        "C":"Pitbull",
        "D":"None of the Above"
      },
      "answer":"C"
    },
    {
      "question":"Which country successfully test-launched its first hypersonic aircraft?",
      "options":{
        "A":"India",
        "B":"China",
        "C":"Russia",
        "D":"USA"
      },
      "answer":"B"
    },
    {
      "question":"Name the farthest star that was recently seen by NASA’s Hubble Space Telescope?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Alpha Orionis",
        "B":"Proxima Centauri",
        "C":"Icarus",
        "D":"Procyon"
      },
      "answer":"C"
    },
    {
      "question":"Which IIT institute installed India’s first 5G radio laboratory?",
      "options":{
        "A":"IIT-Lucknow",
        "B":"IIT-Kanpur",
        "C":"IIT-Roorkee",
        "D":"IIT-Delhi"
      },
      "answer":"D"
    },
    {
      "question":"In which city of California is Sea World located?",
      "options":{
        "A":"San Francisco",
        "B":"San Diego",
        "C":"Santa Barbara",
        "D":"Los Angeles"
      },
      "answer":"B"
    },
    {
      "question":"Which of the Great Lakes is the only one to lie entirely in the United States?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Lake Huron",
        "B":"Lake Superior",
        "C":"Lake Erie",
        "D":"Lake Michigan"
      },
      "answer":"D"
    },
	{
      "question":"In which state does the Snake River originate?",
      "options":{
        "A":"Colorado",
        "B":"Wyoming",
        "C":"Iowa",
        "D":"Idaho"
      },
      "answer":"B"
    },
	{
      "question":"How many states are there in the United States of America?",
      "options":{
        "A":"49",
        "B":"50",
        "C":"51",
        "D":"52"
      },
      "answer":"B"
    },
    {
        "question":" If it is 6.00 a.m. in New York what is the time in Los Angeles?",
        "options":{
          "A":"6.00 a.m",
          "B":"5.00 a.m",
          "C":"3.00 a.m",
          "D":"4.00 a.m"
        },
        "answer":"C"
      },
      {
          "question":"Which is the 49th State of USA?",
          "options":{
            "A":"Alaska",
            "B":"Georgia",
            "C":"Texas",
            "D":"California"
          },
          "answer":"A"
        }
    ]
}
